A Guide to the Beall Booth Family Papers, 1751-1932
Colonial Williamsburg Foundation
Colonial Williamsburg Foundation
Beall Booth Family Papers, 1751-1932
Colonial Williamsburg Foundation
MS 2009.15
2 Boxes (314 items).
The Beall Booth Family Papers contains 314 items and covers the family line of Samuel Booth of Williamsburg VA, his children and grandchildren from 1751-1785.
Beall family; Booth family
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Purchase, 2009.
Biographical Information
Samuel Beall (1748-1793), pronounced Bell, was a prominent merchant in Williamsburg, VA. ?b Born in 1748 to the descendants of Scottish immigrants he operated a store in Williamsburg from 1779 to 1785. He received a land grant for 40,000 acres in Jefferson County Kentucky, which he partnered with John May of Williamsburg to survey and rent. Married in 1779 to Ann Booth (1751-1786), he had 4 children; Norborne Booth Beall (1780-1844), Matilda Aylett Beall (1782-1822) who married William Galt, Harriet Beall who married Richard A. Maupin (1779-1827), and Louisa Brooke Beall. Norborne Booth Beall (1780-1844) took interest in Samuel Beall's (1748-1793) land claims and after Samuel Beall's death in 1793 he went about the process closing his accounts and moving west. The Estate of Samuel Beall (1748-1793) still had outstanding debts and other business that was dealt with through the lawyer James Semple (1768-1834). Ann Pasteur Maupin, daughter of huegunot Tavern owner Gabriel Maupin of Williamsburg, married Norborne Booth Beall (1780-1844) in 1799. Norborne Booth Beall (1780-1844) was a classmate of her brother Richard A. Maupin (1779-1827) at the College of William and Mary. They, and the younger brother Edward Maupin, settled Jefferson County Kentucky with the Galt Family in 1803. Norborne Booth Beall (1780-1844) and Ann Pasteur Maupin had several children. Their eldest daughter Ann Matilda Beall (1800-1859) married her cousin William Lee Booth (1796-1868), West Point Graduate and veteran of 1812, and they raised a family in Meade County Kentucky. They had nine children: Clara A. Booth (1820-1908), Norborne M. Booth (1822-1909), Harriet Maria Booth (1824-1908), William L. Booth (1827-1893), Waller S. Booth (1829-1921), Galt Worthington Booth (1832-1921), Charles H. W. Booth, Sarah Louisa Booth, and Meade Booth. At some point a portion of the family migrated to Indiana, but stayed in close contact with each other. Galt Worthington Booth (1832-1921), a doctor like his uncle Edward Maupin, joined the union army during the Civil War and served as a hospital steward.
Scope and Content
The collection covers the business and personal papers of the Beall Booth family during the years of 1753-1932. The business papers are mostly from the 18th century (1753-1835), created by Samuel Beall (1748-1793), Norborne Booth Beall (1780-1844), William Lee Booth (1796), John May, William Scott, and James Semple (1768-1834). They contain bonds, receipts, contracts, memos, notes, and correspondence from the accounts of the Beall Family, as operated by the family and the lawyers who managed their estates. Much of the business papers address the land claims of Samuel Beall (1748-1793) and Norborne Booth Beall (1780-1844) in Kentucky, surveyed and managed with John May. There is a map from 1794 separated from the collection. The bulk of the business documents end at 1811, with two documents from the 1830s.
The personal papers are primarily from the 19th century. With one document from pre-1824, a prayer book given by Gabriel Maupin to his wife. They focus on the Booth family decendants of Samuel Beall in Kentucky, with some family mementos from the Maupin family who migrated with the Beall Family to Kentucky. They contain mostly correspondence between William Lee Booth, his children, and friends of the family between the 1850s and 1870s. Many of the letters are written to and from Galt Worthington Booth (1832-1921), who was a hospital steward for the Union Army during the Civil War. While the family writes on the Civil War, they mostly write about day to day life. The personal papers also contain some bible pages containing family genealogy, pamphlets, and photographs of the family. The pamphlets include the prayer book, a notebook, a young man's guide to the bridal chamber, and a copy of a speech given during the peace talks prior to the Civil War. There are no documents from the 1840s, and only one document from post 1875. A note pretaining to a daguerreotype by Margaret S. Booth from 1932.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged in two series, each a box containing eleven folders. The first series contains the business papers of the family, mostly from the later part of the 18th century. The papers are organized by person and then date. The second series contains the personal papers of the family, primarily from the 19th century, in one box of eleven folders. The folders are arranged by document type; with the correspondence further arranged by recipient, sender, and date.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Separated Material
Separated from collection a map of The middle dominions of the United States of America 1794. Located in special collections oversized materials by Laurie and Whittle 1794 May 12.
Index Terms
Beall, Samuel, 1748-1793; Beall, Norborne Booth, 1780-1843; Booth, William Lee, 1796-1868--Correspondence; Booth, Clara A., 1820-1908--Correspondence; Booth, Waller S., 1829-1898--Correspondence; Booth, N. M. (Norborne M.)--Correspondence; Booth, Galt Worthington, 1832-1921--Correspondence; May, John; Maupin, Richard A., 1779-1827--Correspondance; Scott, William; Semple, James, 1768-1834--Correspondence; Agriculture--Kentucky--Meade County; Land use--Kentucky--Meade County; Land use--Kentucky--Jefferson County; Kentucky--Politics and government--1792-1865; Surveying--Kentucky--Meade County; Surveying--Kentucky--Jefferson County; Pioneers--Kentucky--Meade County; Pioneers--Kentucky--Jefferson County; Physicians--Kentucky--Meade County; Indiana--Politics and government--1861-1865; Physicians--Indiana--Leavenworth; Business Records--Virginia; Merchants--Virginia--Williamsburg; United States--History--Civil War, 1851-1865; United States--History--Civil War,1861-1865--Hospitals; Booth family; Beal family
Contents List
- Business Papers 1753-1835, 1 box (Box-folder 109:1-11)
  The business papers are mostly from the 18th century, created by Samuel Beall, Norborne Booth Beall, William Lee Booth, John May, William Scott, and James Semple. They contain bonds, receipts, contracts, memos, notes, and correspondence. The business papers deal with the accounts of the Beall Family, as operated by the family and the lawyers who managed their estates. Much of the business papers address the land claims of Samuel Beall and Norborne Booth Beall in Kentucky, bought and managed with John May.
  Each folder is organized by the creator, and then chronological with papers dealing with the same person grouped together.
  - 1 folder (Box-folder 109:1)
    Parchment with "Nicolas vs. Beale" on one side and "Old original copy ac/ts" on inner side.
  - William Scott Papers, 1753-1775, 1 folder (Box-folder 109:2)
    Business documents managed by William Scott. Mostly bonds and receipts.
    - 1769 August 6 (Box-folder 109:2)
    - 1769 August 6 (Box-folder 109:2)
    - 1774 December 7 (Box-folder 109:2)
    - 1774 February 26 (Box-folder 109:2)
    - 1773 May 5 (Box-folder 109:2)
    - 1772 December 3 (Box-folder 109:2)
    - 1768 March 10 (Box-folder 109:2)
    - 1767 March 9 (Box-folder 109:2)
    - 1765 August 10 (Box-folder 109:2)
    - 1765 August 10 (Box-folder 109:2)
    - 1769 (Box-folder 109:2)
    - (Box-folder 109:2)
    - (Box-folder 109:2)
    - 1761 June 16 (Box-folder 109:2)
    - 1768 January 18 (Box-folder 109:2)
    - 1763 April 28 (Box-folder 109:2)
    - 1768 July 6 (Box-folder 109:2)
    - 1765 August 7 (Box-folder 109:2)
    - 1765 December 9 (Box-folder 109:2)
    - 1766 March 19 (Box-folder 109:2)
    - 1767 March 7 (Box-folder 109:2)
    - 1767 June 26 (Box-folder 109:2)
    - 1768 Jume 15 (Box-folder 109:2)
    - 1764 (Box-folder 109:2)
    - 1766-1768 (Box-folder 109:2)
    - 1769 January 5 (Box-folder 109:2)
    - 1769 August 24 (Box-folder 109:2)
    - 1769 October 15 (Box-folder 109:2)
    - 1770 March 8 (Box-folder 109:2)
    - 1770 July 7 (Box-folder 109:2)
    - 1771 August 12 (Box-folder 109:2)
    - 1772 September 10 (Box-folder 109:2)
    - 1773 November 22 (Box-folder 109:2)
    - 1764 June 6 (Box-folder 109:2)
    - 1771 November 2 (Box-folder 109:2)
    - 1772 August 1 (Box-folder 109:2)
    - 1772 February 8 (Box-folder 109:2)
    - 1772 April 6 (Box-folder 109:2)
    - Undated (Box-folder 109:2)
  - Samuel Beall Papers, 1771-1790, 1 folder (Box-folder 109:3)
    Bonds, contracts, and receipts that pertain to the accounts of Samuel Beall.
    - 1774 (Box-folder 109:3)
    - 1771 October 8 (Box-folder 109:3)
    - 1774 March 17 (Box-folder 109:3)
    - 1779 February 1 (Box-folder 109:3)
    - 1790 June 20 (Box-folder 109:3)
    - 1786 October 21 (Box-folder 109:3)
    - 1790 November 1 (Box-folder 109:3)
    - 1781 May 1 (Box-folder 109:3)
    - 1786 November 24 (Box-folder 109:3)
  - John May Papers, 1780-1785, 1 Folder (Box-folder 109:4)
    The contracts, letters, and bonds that cover the beginning of the partnership between Samuel Beall and John May.
    - 1785 May 5 (Box-folder 109:4)
    - 1784 April 9 (Box-folder 109:4)
    - 1784 April 4 (Box-folder 109:4)
    - 1780 September 3 (Box-folder 109:4)
    - 1780 September 3 (Box-folder 109:4)
    - undated (Box-folder 109:4)
    - 1780 April 4 (Box-folder 109:4)
    - 1780 May 6 (Box-folder 109:4)
    - undated (Box-folder 109:4)
    - 1780 February 1 (Box-folder 109:4)
    - 1780 February 1 (Box-folder 109:4)
    - 1781 August 13 (Box-folder 109:4)
    - 1780-1788 (Box-folder 109:4)
    - 1782 December 11 (Box-folder 109:4)
  - John May Papers, 1780-1787, 1 folder (Box-folder 109:5)
    Documents pertaining to John May and Samuel Beall's partnership in land speculation in Kentucky.
    - 1780 (Box-folder 109:5)
    - 1783 October (Box-folder 109:5)
    - 1784 May 6 (Box-folder 109:5)
    - 1791 February 19 (Box-folder 109:5)
    - 1780 February 19 (Box-folder 109:5)
    - 1785 June 30, 5 leaves (Box-folder 109:5)
    - 1785 (Box-folder 109:5)
    - 1785 June 30 (Box-folder 109:5)
    - 1791 February 19 (Box-folder 109:5)
  - Samuel Beall's Estate papers, 1787-1821, 1 folder (Box-folder 109:6)
    Documents regarding the estate of Samuel Beall and the proof of claim in Kentucky.
    - 1787 October 23 (Box-folder 109:6)
    - Undated (Box-folder 109:6)
    - 1807 (Box-folder 109:6)
    - 1793-1805 (Box-folder 109:6)
    - Undated (Box-folder 109:6)
    - 1804 (Box-folder 109:6)
    - 1793 September 11 (Box-folder 109:6)
    - 1792 March 9 (Box-folder 109:6)
    - 1815 April 26 (Box-folder 109:6)
    - Undated (Box-folder 109:6)
    - 1796 November 11 (Box-folder 109:6)
    - 1795 February 17 (Box-folder 109:6)
    - Undated (Box-folder 109:6)
    - 1821 (Box-folder 109:6)
  - Norborne Booth Beall Papers, 1798-1824, 1 folder (Box-folder 109:7)
    Accounts and other financial documents pertaining to Norborne Booth Beall.
    - 1798-1800 (Box-folder 109:7)
    - 1799-1800 (Box-folder 109:7)
    - 1799-1800 (Box-folder 109:7)
    - 1800 (Box-folder 109:7)
    - 1800 (Box-folder 109:7)
    - 1800-1801 (Box-folder 109:7)
    - 1801-1802 (Box-folder 109:7)
    - 1800-1801 (Box-folder 109:7)
    - 1801 (Box-folder 109:7)
    - 1824 August 12 (Box-folder 109:7)
    - 1801-1802 (Box-folder 109:7)
    - 1802 (Box-folder 109:7)
    - 1802 (Box-folder 109:7)
    - 1801-1803 (Box-folder 109:7)
  - 1799-1837, 1 folder (Box-folder 109:8)
    Receipts and bills from the finances of Norborne Booth Beall.
    - 1808 June 2 (Box-folder 109:8)
    - 1808 July 1 (Box-folder 109:8)
    - 1813 October 27 (Box-folder 109:8)
    - 1820 (Box-folder 109:8)
    - 1821 January 18 (Box-folder 109:8)
    - 1806 (Box-folder 109:8)
    - 1806-1808, 6 leaves (Box-folder 109:8)
    - 1807 (Box-folder 109:8)
    - 1807-1808 (Box-folder 109:8)
    - Undated (Box-folder 109:8)
    - 1820 March 28 (Box-folder 109:8)
    - 1820 February 15 (Box-folder 109:8)
    - 1820 February 14 (Box-folder 109:8)
    - 1820 February 12 (Box-folder 109:8)
    - 1820 Febrary 12 (Box-folder 109:8)
    - 1820 February 11 (Box-folder 109:8)
    - 1820 February 10 (Box-folder 109:8)
    - 1793-1804 (Box-folder 109:8)
    - 1795 (Box-folder 109:8)
    - 1806 June 28 (Box-folder 109:8)
    - 1808 December 31 (Box-folder 109:8)
    - 1819 (Box-folder 109:8)
    - 1819 July 12 (Box-folder 109:8)
    - 1821 February 11 (Box-folder 109:8)
    - 1801 January 22 (Box-folder 109:8)
    - 1799 December 6 (Box-folder 109:8)
    - 1802 (Box-folder 109:8)
    - 1803 August 27 (Box-folder 109:8)
    - 1806 April 9 (Box-folder 109:8)
    - 1808 February 21 (Box-folder 109:8)
    - 1808 February 21 (Box-folder 109:8)
    - 1808 March 4 (Box-folder 109:8)
    - 1808 Febrary 22 (Box-folder 109:8)
    - 1808 February 24 (Box-folder 109:8)
    - 1806 (Box-folder 109:8)
    - 1811 September 24 (Box-folder 109:8)
    - 1811 April 13 (Box-folder 109:8)
    - 1821 (Box-folder 109:8)
    - 1821 June 29 (Box-folder 109:8)
    - 1825? August 7 (Box-folder 109:8)
    - 1825 February 16 (Box-folder 109:8)
    - 1837 March 31 (Box-folder 109:8)
    - 1810 (Box-folder 109:8)
    - 1811 (Box-folder 109:8)
    - 1811 (Box-folder 109:8)
    - Undated (Box-folder 109:8)
    - Undated (Box-folder 109:8)
    - Undated (Box-folder 109:8)
    - Undated (Box-folder 109:8)
    - Undated (Box-folder 109:8)
    - Undated (Box-folder 109:8)
    - Undated (Box-folder 109:8)
    - Undated (Box-folder 109:8)
    - Undated (Box-folder 109:8)
    - Undated (Box-folder 109:8)
  - 1798-1820, 1 folder (Box-folder 109:9)
    Contains receipts settling accounts from the estate of Samuel Beall, as handled by James Semple. More receipts and documents from the finances of Norborne Booth Beall.
    - 1801 (Box-folder 109:9)
    - 1802 March 2 (Box-folder 109:9)
    - 1802 July 13 (Box-folder 109:9)
    - 1808 February 21 (Box-folder 109:9)
    - 1808 February 23 (Box-folder 109:9)
    - 1808 February 28 (Box-folder 109:9)
    - 1808 March 1 (Box-folder 109:9)
    - 1808 March 1 (Box-folder 109:9)
    - 1809 January 20 (Box-folder 109:9)
    - 1808 (Box-folder 109:9)
    - 1811 October 1 (Box-folder 109:9)
    - 1811 October (Box-folder 109:9)
    - 1803 (Box-folder 109:9)
    - 1804 (Box-folder 109:9)
    - 1805 (Box-folder 109:9)
    - Circa 1805 (Box-folder 109:9)
    - 1805 June 12 (Box-folder 109:9)
    - 1805 December 26 (Box-folder 109:9)
    - 1808 December (Box-folder 109:9)
    - 1809 April 12 (Box-folder 109:9)
    - 1809 June 12 (Box-folder 109:9)
    - 1809 October 1 (Box-folder 109:9)
    - 1809 December 12 (Box-folder 109:9)
    - 1810 July 7 (Box-folder 109:9)
    - 1810 September 19 (Box-folder 109:9)
    - 1811 January 10 (Box-folder 109:9)
    - 1811 March 12 (Box-folder 109:9)
    - 1810-1811 (Box-folder 109:9)
    - 1812-1813 (Box-folder 109:9)
    - 1805 August 26 (Box-folder 109:9)
    - 1807 May 27 (Box-folder 109:9)
    - 1808 December 18 (Box-folder 109:9)
    - 1809 November 10 (Box-folder 109:9)
    - 1810 June 13 (Box-folder 109:9)
    - 1802 July 11 (Box-folder 109:9)
    - 1806 July 24 (Box-folder 109:9)
    - 1806 May 6 (Box-folder 109:9)
    - 1806 (Box-folder 109:9)
    - 1808 December 16 (Box-folder 109:9)
    - 1807 September 10 (Box-folder 109:9)
    - 1808 September 17 (Box-folder 109:9)
    - Articles of Agreement John Ridgway with Norborne Booth Beall,"> 1810 June 12 (Box-folder 109:9)
    - 1810 September 5 (Box-folder 109:9)
    - 1810 October 2 (Box-folder 109:9)
    - 1810 November 19 (Box-folder 109:9)
    - 1810 November 19 (Box-folder 109:9)
    - 1802 March 30 (Box-folder 109:9)
    - 1802 July 12 (Box-folder 109:9)
    - 1802 (Box-folder 109:9)
    - 1802 July 12 (Box-folder 109:9)
    - 1802 (Box-folder 109:9)
    - 1802 (Box-folder 109:9)
    - 1802 July 12 (Box-folder 109:9)
    - 1802 July 12 (Box-folder 109:9)
    - 1802 July 16 (Box-folder 109:9)
    - 1807-1809 (Box-folder 109:9)
    - 1807-1809 (Box-folder 109:9)
    - 1809 February 7 (Box-folder 109:9)
    - 1809-1810 (Box-folder 109:9)
    - 1811 February 12 (Box-folder 109:9)
    - 1810 March 16 (Box-folder 109:9)
    - 1810 June 1 (Box-folder 109:9)
    - 1811 March 19 (Box-folder 109:9)
    - 1810 September 29 (Box-folder 109:9)
    - 1811 November 12 (Box-folder 109:9)
    - 1811 July 2 (Box-folder 109:9)
    - 1811 (Box-folder 109:9)
    - 1811 August 20 (Box-folder 109:9)
    - 1811 May 5 (Box-folder 109:9)
    - 1811 October 18 (Box-folder 109:9)
    - 1820 September 8 (Box-folder 109:9)
  - 1796-1807, 1 folder (Box-folder 109:10)
    Receipts, bills, and letters from Norborne Booth Beall's finances.
    - 1804 November 21 (Box-folder 109:10)
    - 1796 August 2 (Box-folder 109:10)
    - 1802 February 20 (Box-folder 109:10)
    - 1802 March 31 (Box-folder 109:10)
    - Undated (Box-folder 109:10)
    - 1801 April 6 (Box-folder 109:10)
    - 1801 (Box-folder 109:10)
    - Undated (Box-folder 109:10)
    - 1801 May 20 (Box-folder 109:10)
    - 1801 (Box-folder 109:10)
    - 1800 (Box-folder 109:10)
    - 1800 (Box-folder 109:10)
    - 1800 (Box-folder 109:10)
    - 1798 (Box-folder 109:10)
    - Undated (Box-folder 109:10)
    - 1799 December 18 (Box-folder 109:10)
    - 1800 May 24 (Box-folder 109:10)
    - 1800 May 31 (Box-folder 109:10)
    - 1800 June 24 (Box-folder 109:10)
    - 1807 April 29 (Box-folder 109:10)
    - Undated (Box-folder 109:10)
  - William Lee Booth, 1834-1835, 1 folder (Box-folder 109:11)
    Contains William Lee Booth note on his copy of the division of land claims in Kentucky and an account summary.
    - 1835 April 8 (Box-folder 109:11)
    - 1834 (Box-folder 109:11)
- Personal Papers, 1751-1932, 1 box (Box-folder 110:1-11)
  The personal papers are primarily from the 19th century. They focus on the Booth family in Kentucky, with some family mementos from the Maupin family who migrated with the Beall Family to Kentucky. They contain mostly correspondence between William Lee Booth, his children, and friends of the family. Many of the letters are written to and from Galt Worthington Booth, who was a hospital steward for the Union Army during the Civil War. While the family writes on the Civil War, they mostly write about day to day life. The personal papers also contain some photos, pamphlets, and photographs of the family. The pamphlets include a prayer book that belonged to Gabriel Maupin, a notebook, a young man's guide to the bridal chamber, and a copy of a speech given during the peace talks prior to the Civil War.
  The eleven folders are arranged by document type as found; with the correspondence further arranged by recipient, sender, and date.
  - Poems, 1824-1834, 1 folder (Box-folder 110:1)
    Contains poems by E. A. M. Balfour, Ingnatius Reynolds, C. M. Cooms, Lt. Henry Smith, and Rev. Mr. Abell,
    - 1834 February 28 (Box-folder 110:1)
    - Undated (Box-folder 110:1)
    - Undated (Box-folder 110:1)
    - Undated (Box-folder 110:1)
    - 1834 March 1 (Box-folder 110:1)
    - 1834 February 6 (Box-folder 110:1)
    - 1824 January 5 (Box-folder 110:1)
    - Undated (Box-folder 110:1)
  - Family Kept Genealogy, undated, 1 folder (Box-folder 110:2)
    Contains a page from the Booth family register, and several pages from the Beall-Booth family bible with the family history writen in pencil.
    - Undated (Box-folder 110:2)
    - Undated (Box-folder 110:2)
    - Undated (Box-folder 110:2)
    - Undated (Box-folder 110:2)
    - Undated (Box-folder 110:2)
  - Miscellainus books 1751, 1 folder (Box-folder 110:3)
    A prayer book that Gabriel Maupin gave to his wife in 1751, and a notebook containing notes about pig rearing.
    - 1751 (Box-folder 110:3)
    - Notebook Undated (Box-folder 110:3)
  - Edward Maupin, undated-1932, 1 folder (Box-folder 110:4)
    Contains a Daguerreotype of Edward Maupin with no date, and a note pretaining to the photograph found with the item by Margaret S. Booth 1932 January 14.
    - Undated (Box-folder 110:4)
    - 1932 January 14 (Box-folder 110:4)
  - Theory and Practice of Medicine: Notes from Lectures of Prof. Reese Castleton Medical College (Spring Session), 1842, 1 folder (1 pamphlet, 23 leaves) (Box-folder 110:5)
    Contains notes from the lectures of Prof. Reese, Theory and Practice of Medicine.
  - Letters to Clara A. Booth, 1851-1874, 1 folder (Box-folder 110:6)
    Letters written to Clara Booth from family and friends. Topics discussed, day to day life, and courtship. Several of the letters are from Galt Worthington Booth during his time in the Union Army, he talks about camp life, camp illnesses, courtship, and matters relating to the family.
    - 1851 June 2 (Box-folder 110:6)
    - 1854 June 11 (Box-folder 110:6)
    - 1855 February 2 (Box-folder 110:6)
    - 1858 June 18 (Box-folder 110:6)
    - 1861 April 21 (Box-folder 110:6)
    - 1861 December 26 (Box-folder 110:6)
    - 1862 June 25 (Box-folder 110:6)
    - 1862 March 22 (Box-folder 110:6)
    - 1862 June 8 (Box-folder 110:6)
    - 1863 May 17 (Box-folder 110:6)
    - 1863 October 19 (Box-folder 110:6)
    - 1857 October 3 (Box-folder 110:6)
    - 1864 August 15 (Box-folder 110:6)
    - 1874 May 27 (Box-folder 110:6)
  - Letters written to Galt Worthington Booth, 1860-1861, 1 folder (Box-folder 110:7)
    Letter written to Galt Worthington Booth from family. They write to him about the upcoming War, his joining of the Union Army, and day-to-day life.
    - 1860 April 16 (Box-folder 110:7)
    - 1861 January 11 (Box-folder 110:7)
    - 1861 March 2 (Box-folder 110:7)
    - 1861 May 6 (Box-folder 110:7)
    - 1861 June 18 (Box-folder 110:7)
    - 1861 January 14 (Box-folder 110:7)
    - 1861 April 8 (Box-folder 110:7)
    - 1861 May 11 (Box-folder 110:7)
  - Letters to Galt Worthington Booth, 1861-1887, 1 Folder (Box-folder 110:8)
    Letters written to Galt Worthington Booth from friends. They write to him about his political envolvement in Kentucky, his medical business at home, and day-to-day life. One of the letters is an invitation to a 1887 battle reenactment that his company was involved in.
    - 1861 January 22 (Box-folder 110:8)
    - 1861 February 21 (Box-folder 110:8)
    - 1861 May 18 (Box-folder 110:8)
    - 1861 April 8 (Box-folder 110:8)
    - Undated (Box-folder 110:8)
    - 1861 May 14 (Box-folder 110:8)
    - 1861 May 24 (Box-folder 110:8)
    - 1861 March 13 (Box-folder 110:8)
    - 1887 (Box-folder 110:8)
    - 1865 August 18 (Box-folder 110:8)
  - Letters to Waller S. Booth, 1862, 1 folder (Box-folder 110:9)
    Letters written to Waller S. Booth from Family. Galt Worthington Booth writes from the various hospital camps that he serves as steward; discussing his position within the army, camp life, and camp illnesses. The other letters talk about Galt Worthington Booth and day-to-day life of the family.
    - 1862 June 25 (Box-folder 110:9)
    - 1862 August 8 (Box-folder 110:9)
    - 1862 April 12 (Box-folder 110:9)
    - 1862 May 14 (Box-folder 110:9)
    - 1862 November 17 (Box-folder 110:9)
    - 1862 June 18 (Box-folder 110:9)
    - 1862 April 18 (Box-folder 110:9)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1861-1875, 1 folder (Box-folder 110:10)
    Miscellenius correspondence between the Beall-Booth Family and a pamphlet of a speech given during the peace talks prior to the Civil War. The family talks about military position, courtship, daily life, and the family history.
    - 1862 September 8 (Box-folder 110:10)
    - 1861 August 17 (Box-folder 110:10)
    - 1861 June 3 (Box-folder 110:10)
    - 1862 April 12 (Box-folder 110:10)
    - 1875 April 24 (Box-folder 110:10)
    - 1861 March 2 (Box-folder 110:10)